export const FOODANDNUTRITIONA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. During Million’s test, the precipitate formed on heating turns",
A: "pink",
B: "reddish brown",
C: "yellow",
D: "golden brown",
answer: "B. reddish brown",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following options describe an effective kitchen layout?",
A: "Arrangement of kitchen equipment",
B: "Sizes of the kitchen equipment",
C: "Colour scheme of the kitchen",
D: "Size of the kitchen",
answer: "A. Arrangement of kitchen equipment",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The best flour for bread is",
A: "strong wheat flour",
B: "soft wheat flour",
C: "self-raising flour",
D: "composite flour",
answer: "A. strong wheat flour",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. An example of a meat dish is",
A: "kedgeree",
B: "croquette",
C: "yam ball",
D: "sausage roll",
answer: "D. sausage roll",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. In order to prevent food poisoning, a caterer should",
A: "store food can after opening",
B: "wash hands thoroughly before handling food",
C: "keep leftover food in the cupboard",
D: "return thawed food to the freezer",
answer: "B. wash hands thoroughly before handling food",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A suitable method for preparing sponge cake is",
A: "rubbing-in method",
B: "creaming method",
C: "whisking method",
D: "melting method",
answer: "B. creaming method",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following statements are true of beverages?  \nI. They refresh and quench thirst  \nII. They are nourishing  \nIII. They are stimulants  \nIV. They protect the body",
A: "II, Ill and IV only",
B: "I, III and IV only",
C: "l, II and IV only",
D: "I, II and III only",
answer: "D. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. When choking occurs, food is trapped in the",
A: "trachea",
B: "diaphragm",
C: "oesophagus",
D: "intestines",
answer: "A. trachea",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. A shopping list is a/the",
A: "list of items and their prices",
B: "guide used when purchasing items",
C: "list of ingredients and their quantities",
D: "total number of items to buy",
answer: "B. guide used when purchasing items",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The common food poisoning bacteria in chicken is",
A: "Salmonella typhimurium",
B: "Staphylococcus aureus",
C: "Clostridium botulinum",
D: "Bacillus cereus",
answer: "A. Salmonella typhimurium",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following substances is responsible for the stimulating effect in tea?",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "A. Caffeine",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A disadvantage of convenient foods is that they",
A: "expire quickly",
B: "are processed foods",
C: "are expensive",
D: "have prolonged cooking time",
answer: "C. are expensive",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. In order to save time and energy during cooking, the appropriate material for a saucepan is",
A: "earth",
B: "enamel",
C: "stainless steel",
D: "galvanized iron",
answer: "C. stainless steel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Addition of sugar to fruits improves the",
A: "texture",
B: "colour",
C: "flavour",
D: "appearance",
answer: "C. flavour",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following fruits is the least source of Vitamin C?",
A: "Orange",
B: "Banana",
C: "Mango",
D: "Guava",
answer: "B. Banana",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Caffeine in coffee gives a/an",
A: "satiety effect",
B: "aromatic effect",
C: "stimulating effect",
D: "sedative effect",
answer: "C. stimulating effect",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. An example of a ready to serve convenience food is",
A: "instant tea",
B: "canned fish",
C: "coffee",
D: "cake mix",
answer: "B. canned fish",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. An appropriate material for wrapping turnovers for sale is",
A: "cling film",
B: "aluminium foil",
C: "waxed paper",
D: "paper envelop",
answer: "C. waxed paper",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Foods prepared from unwholesome ingredients with the aim of maximizing profit are said to be",
A: "adulterated",
B: "misbranded",
C: "enriched",
D: "fortified",
answer: "A. adulterated",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The most effective means of collecting data from villagers on lesser-known dishes is",
A: "survey",
B: "administration of questionnaire",
C: "observation and participation",
D: "interview",
answer: "C. observation and participation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following food items has been preserved by a combination of salting and smoking?",
A: "tuna flakes",
B: "fermented fish",
C: "stock fish",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "C. stock fish",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Réchauffé is best explained as",
A: "economy of cooking",
B: "leftover food",
C: "leftover cooker",
D: "warming food",
answer: "B. leftover food",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Dry, canned and bottled foods should be kept in a",
A: "refrigerator",
B: "cupboard",
C: "warmer",
D: "freezer",
answer: "B. cupboard",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. In the kitchen, tea towels are used for",
A: "wiping washed dishes",
B: "holding hot saucepans",
C: "lining serving trays",
D: "wiping dirty surfaces",
answer: "A. wiping washed dishes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The best cookware for rockbuns is a",
A: "loaf tin",
B: "cake pan",
C: "baking sheet",
D: "patty tin",
answer: "D. patty tin",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. A factor to be considered when selecting meat for grilling is the",
A: "water content",
B: "cut",
C: "fat content",
D: "colour",
answer: "B. cut",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A kitchen sink that is blocked by geese should be cleaned with",
A: "Sulphuric acid",
B: "Soapy water",
C: "Boiling water",
D: "Sink plunger",
answer: "D. Sink plunger",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. When purchasing fresh fish an indication of quality is its",
A: "deep sunken eyes",
B: "flabby flesh",
C: "limp tail",
D: "reddish gills",
answer: "D. reddish gills",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Any food which has been cooked, cooled and turned into another dish is referred to as",
A: "recooked",
B: "réchauffé",
C: "reheated",
D: "reboiled",
answer: "B. réchauffé",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. During cooking, heat is transferred to a saucepan by",
A: "conduction",
B: "convection and radiation",
C: "radiation and conduction",
D: "radiation",
answer: "C. radiation and conduction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Strengthening of bones and teeth is a function of calcium and",
A: "sodium",
B: "phosphorus",
C: "iron",
D: "iodine",
answer: "B. phosphorus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Comparison of prices and values of items before shopping enables consumers to",
A: "buy on impulse",
B: "buy cheaper items",
C: "spend wisely",
D: "buy in bulk",
answer: "C. spend wisely",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The most important factor to consider when preparing family food budget is the",
A: "money available",
B: "foods in season",
C: "size of the kitchen",
D: "storage facility",
answer: "A. money available",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. What is the proportion of fat to flour in short crust pastry?",
A: "1/2 : 1",
B: "1 : 1/2",
C: "1 : 1",
D: "2 : 1",
answer: "C. 1 : 1",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Fat is used to shorten baked flour products in order to make them",
A: "soft and shiny",
B: "soft and crumbly",
C: "crispy and flappy",
D: "crispy and shiny",
answer: "B. soft and crumbly",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. In cookery, the functions of flavourings and, condiments are to  \nI. improves nutritive value of food  \nII. act as preservatives  \nIII. improve flavour of food I \nV. make food presentation easier",
A: "I and III only",
B: "I, II and III only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "II and IV only",
answer: "A. I and III only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Short crust pastry is best made",
A: "Oat flour",
B: "maize flour",
C: "wheat flour",
D: "rice flour",
answer: "C. wheat flour",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. On a formal invitation card” R.S.V.P” is written at the",
A: "upper left",
B: "upper right",
C: "centre left",
D: "bottom right",
answer: "D. bottom right",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The most effective materials for cleaning aluminium pans are",
A: "wire sponge and soap",
B: "sponge and sand",
C: "steel wool and soap",
D: "scouring pad and detergent",
answer: "D. scouring pad and detergent",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Classes of fish include",
A: "white, oily and shell fish",
B: "dry, fresh and shell fish",
C: "bony, dry and white fish",
D: "bony, fresh and oily fish",
answer: "A. white, oily and shell fish",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A child with poor teeth formation and knocked knees is deficient in",
A: "calcium and vitamin K",
B: "iodine and vitamin D",
C: "calcium and vitamin D",
D: "iodine and vitamin K",
answer: "C. calcium and vitamin D",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. First class proteins are of high biological value because they",
A: "contain essential amino acids",
B: "repair worn out tissues",
C: "are of high nutritive value",
D: "contain essential nutrients",
answer: "A. contain essential amino acids",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. In a menu, hors d’oeuvres serve as",
A: "savoury dishes",
B: "sweet dishes",
C: "appetizers",
D: "desserts",
answer: "C. appetizers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A conservative method of egg cookery is",
A: "boiling",
B: "flying",
C: "poaching",
D: "stewing",
answer: "C. poaching",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. An example of a table linen is",
A: "food cover",
B: "tray cloth",
C: "tea towel",
D: "dish cloth",
answer: "B. napkin",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The tools used to gather information for research are called",
A: "instruments",
B: "sample size",
C: "study area",
D: "data",
answer: "A. instruments",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The type of service that is suitable for entertaining a large group of people is",
A: "tray service",
B: "buffet service",
C: "place service",
D: "formal service",
answer: "B. buffet service",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The main aim of blanching vegetables before freezing is to",
A: "improve texture",
B: "reduce cooking time",
C: "maintain colour",
D: "stop enzymatic action",
answer: "D. stop enzymatic action",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The enzyme that converts starch in food to maltose is",
A: "pepsin",
B: "ptyalin",
C: "renin",
D: "trypsin",
answer: "B. ptyalin",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Flaky pastry becomes tough and hard when",
A: "cooking time is prolonged",
B: "cooking time is short",
C: "insufficient water is added",
D: "too much water is added",
answer: "D. too much water is added",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. In bread making, yeast cells are destroyed by the addition of excess",
A: "sugar",
B: "milk",
C: "water",
D: "salt",
answer: "D. salt",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. A dish that requires low oven temperature when cooking is",
A: "rice pudding",
B: "fruit cake",
C: "fruit scone",
D: "milk pudding",
answer: "B. fruit cake",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. Which of the utensils is suitable for creaming and mixing?",
A: "I",
B: "II",
C: "III",
D: "IV",
answer: "B. II",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. The appropriate utensil for turning and lifting food is",
A: "I",
B: "II",
C: "III",
D: "IV",
answer: "C. III",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. When consumed, which of the following dishes takes longer to digest?",
A: "Rice pudding",
B: "Groundnut soup and boiled rice",
C: "Vegetable soup and fufu",
D: "Moimoi/Oleleh",
answer: "C. Vegetable soup and fufu",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. Which of the following methods is most suitable for cooking sirloin of beef?",
A: "Roasting",
B: "Braising",
C: "Boiling",
D: "Broiling",
answer: "A. Roasting",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. The nutrient that spares protein from being used for energy generation in the body is",
A: "vitamins",
B: "mineral salts",
C: "carbohydrates",
D: "water",
answer: "C. carbohydrates",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. Prevention of dry skin is a function of vitamin",
A: "D",
B: "C",
C: "B",
D: "A",
answer: "A. D",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. Which of the following vegetables would lose most of its nutrients when boiled?",
A: "carrot",
B: "tomato",
C: "cabbage",
D: "potato",
answer: "C. cabbage",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. A suitable festive lunch for children is",
A: "fish stew and boiled potatoes",
B: "fried chicken and jollof rice",
C: "okro soup and fufu",
D: "fish stew and cassava pottage",
answer: "B. fried chicken and jollof rice",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]